# Pranav Hari

**J** 613-402-5582 

✓ pranavkhari1@gmail.com 

in pranav-hari-5314b5173 

Ç pranavhari2

## Summary

Carleton University 2024 graduate with a B.Eng in Computer Systems Engineering. Experienced in cloud development, machine learning and test automation. Proficient in various programming languages such as Python, Java, C++ and Golang. Experienced in cybersecurity and ML. Authorized to work for any Canadian employer (Canadian Citizen) and US employer.

### Technical Skills

Languages/Database: Python, Java, C, C++, SQL, Golang, Bash, JavaScript, PHP, React, Node.js, Typescript Developer Tools: VS Code, Eclipse, Git, Docker, Jira, Jenkins, Spring, JUnit, JFrog, Terraform, Ansible, Nexus, Linux, Tomcat, Application Servers

Frameworks: Flask, Django, FastAPI, Keras, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, LangChain, Full-stack Development

Cloud/Databases (AWS): Lambda, SQS, Kinesis Stream, EC2, S3, DynamoDB, CloudFront, CloudWatch, Sagemaker,

Microservice architectures

#### Education

## Carleton University, Ottawa

B.Eng in Computer Systems Engineering

 $\mathbf{Sep}\ \mathbf{2019} - \mathbf{Apr}\ \mathbf{2024}$ 

GPA: 3.7/4.0

## Work Experience

Trend Micro Ottawa, ON

Software Developer Co-op

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022, May 2023 - Aug 2023

- · Utlized event-driven functionality on AWS Kinesis using Java and AWS Lambda to reduce database costs and time
- Used knowledge of AWS development to create a monitoring feature on Cloudwatch to monitor event traffic from agents
- Investigated solutions to implement Redis within the existing AWS architecture
- Developed solutions for customers involving Active Directory and LDAP
- Enhanced existing Java libraries to improve developer workflow and enhance user experience

Nokia Ottawa, ON

Software Developer Intern

- Jan 2022 Aug 2022
- Developed CI/CD Jenkins pipelines in Groovy and shell to maintain and test docker images for product containers
   Integrated security features such as Anchore to scan docker images for malware and vulnerabilities as a part of the DevSecOps process
- Configured and deployed Virtual Machines (VMs) on OpenStack using Terraform
- Maintained infrastructure using Ansible and ran regression tests on VMs hosted on OpenStack
- Used Golang to enhance security features of a test automation framework

Uniqin.ai Remote

Software Engineer Intern

May 2021 - Aug 2021

- Created a web scraping algorithm that fetched competitor prices for the Price Watch feature of uniQin's shopify product
- Utilized Python and FastAPI to successfully send API requests, design custom REST APIs and routers
- Structured user requests through an AWS SQS queue to control request traffic
- Applied knowledge of SQL, postgreSQL queries to effectively manage user data
- Utilized knowledge of VueJS and the Quasar framework to create a user-friendly UI Application

# **Projects**

#### Air Quality Monitoring System

September 2023 - April 2024

- \* Accurately predicted air quality data in an indoor environment using an ML model created using scikit-learn
- \* Deployed ML model to a Sagemaker endpoint to create an ML workflow for accurate VOC prediction
- \* Applied knowledge of backend development to create APIs and develop a full-stack IoT monitoring system

### Certifications

Generative AI with Large Language Models by DeepLearning.AI (Coursera)